const questions = [
  {
    info:
      'Satellites are objects that orbit planets, a moon is a natural satellite. Earth has one moon, Mars has 2 moons and Jupiter has a whopping 79 known moons!',
    question:
      'How many more moons does Jupiter have than Earth and Mars together?',
    questionType: 'input',
    expectedAnswer: '76',
    explanation:
      'Earth and Mars together have 3 moons. If we take 3 from 79, we should get 76.',
  },
  {
    info:
      'Our solar system has eight planets. They are,  in order: Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune. The inner four planets are rocky planets and the outer four are gas giants.',
    question: 'Which planet is the second closest gas giant to the sun?',
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: 'Saturn',
    choices: ['Venus', 'Uranus', 'Earth', 'Saturn'],
    explanation:
      'The gas planets are further from the sun than the four rocky planets. That means we are actually looking for the sixth planet from the sun, which is Saturn.',
  },
  {
    info:
      'Sound travels through the air by particles vibrating and colliding with other particles making them vibrate. Space is a vacuum; a vacuum is an area with nothing in it so there are no particles there. This means sound can not travel in space.',
    question:
      'Could an astronaut living on a space station hear a guitar if he/she were to play it?',
    questionType: 'yes/no',
    expectedAnswer: 'Yes',
    explanation:
      "A space station has air for an astronaut to live there. This means that sound can travel and a person could hear himself/herself playing the guitar. If he/she took the guitar outside the space station and played it, he/she wouldn't be able to hear it in the vacuum of space.",
  },
  {
    info:
      'Our solar system has four gas planets, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune. They are further from the sun and are much bigger than the rocky inner planets. Each of them also has many moons. They are called gas planets because they are balls of hydrogen and helium. ',
    question: 'Could you stand on the surface of one of the gas planets?',
    questionType: 'yes/no',
    expectedAnswer: 'No',
    explanation:
      "Because gases aren't solid you would sink right through the surface of a gas planet. It would be a bit like trying to stand in the air.",
  },
  {
    info:
      'The Apollo 11 mission was the first time a human set foot on the moon. It was Neil Armstrong who took the first small step on the moon. It took just over 4 days for them to reach the moon and they were there for just under a day, including a 7 hour sleep, before taking 3 days to return to Earth.',
    question:
      "How many days did it take for the Apollo 11 mission to reach the moon, visit its surface and return to Earth?",
    questionType: 'input',
    expectedAnswer: '8',
    explanation:
      'We can count the time to reach the moon as 4 days and the time there as 1 day as was is slightly longer and the other is slightly shorter than a full day. This means to figure out how long it took, we have to add 4, 1 and 3. 4 + 1 + 3 = 8.',
  },
  {
    info:
      "The Earth sits at a slight angle in its orbit around the sun. This tilt in the Earth's axis means that different parts of the Earth receive the suns most direct rays. When the North Pole tilts towards the sun, it is summer in the Northern Hemisphere and when the South Pole tilts towards the sun, it is summer in the Southern Hemisphere.",
    question: 'What is it that causes the different seasons?',
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: "The tilt in the Earth's axis.",
    choices: [
      "The tilt in the Earth's axis.",
      'The Earth getting closer and further from the sun throughout the year.',
      'Father Christmas',
    ],
    explanation:
      'The tilt in the Earthâ€™s axis means that at different times of year, different parts of the earth get more direct sunlight. When a part of the Earth is getting more sunlight, it gets warmer(spring/summer) and when a part of the Earth gets less sunlight, it tends to be colder(autumn/winter).',
  },
  {
    info:
      'The asteroid belt is a donut-shaped region in the Solar System, between the fourth and fith planets. It contains a great many solid, irregularly shaped bodies, of many sizes but much smaller than planets, called asteroids or minor planets.',
    question: 'Where is the asteroid belt?',
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: 'Between Mars and Jupiter',
    choices: [
      'Between Earth and Venus',
      'Between Jupiter and Saturn',
      'Between Earth and Mars',
      'Between Mars and Jupiter',
    ],
    explanation:
      'The asteroid belt is found in a region between the planets Mars and Jupiter.',
  },
  {
    info:
      'Most comets are small Solar System bodies with elongated elliptical orbits that take them close to the Sun for a part of their orbit and then out into the further reaches of the Solar System for the remainder.',
    question: 'What are comets mostly made of?',
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: 'Dirty ice and dust',
    choices: [
      'Rusty metal',
      'Dirty ice and dust',
      'Hot, liquid rock',
      'Poisonous liquid',
    ],
    explanation:
      'Comets are mostly made of snow, ice and dust along with some frozen gases.',
  },
  {
    info:
      'Mars is the fourth planet from the Sun and the second-smallest planet in the Solar System, being larger than only Mercury.',
    question: 'How many moons does Mars have?',
    questionType: 'input',
    expectedAnswer: '2',
    explanation: 'Mars has 2 moons, Phobos and Deimos.',
  },
  {
    info:
      'The regolith, of a planet, is the blanket of loose rocks and dust that cover it. The regolith of Mars is has minerals rich in iron, which makes it look red.',
    question: "What gives Mars it's colour?",
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: 'The iron in its surface.',
    choices: ['It has a red sky.', 'The iron in its surface.', 'It is secretly a tomato.'],
    explanation:
      "Iron can often look very red, like rust or how the iron in blood makes it red. As Mars has lots of iron rich minerals in it's surface this gives it the red colour that iron can often have.",
  },
  {
    info:
      'There a lots of things that can have objects in orbit around them. Planets can have moons orbit them, stars have planets, orbit them and black holes are often orbited by solar systems.',
    question: 'What is the sun?',
    questionType: 'multiple',
    expectedAnswer: 'A star',
    choices: ['A planet', 'An asteroid', 'A black hole', 'A star'],
    explanation:
      'The planets in our solar sytem orbit the sun. Because there are planets orbiting the sun we can tell that it is a star.',
  },
];

export { questions };
